JOHN LEINTZ

651-358-1072 • JohnLeintz@scaledflow.com • linkedin.com/in/john-leintz

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

IT experience includes Scrum Master, Software Development, Software Development Team Lead, Test Automation, and Network Administration: adept at working in a fast-paced environment demanding excellent organizational, leadership, and interpersonal skills. I recently participated in an Agile transformation and gained an in-depth understanding of the issues and solutions which are common in many conversions. Combined with multiple SAFe 5.0® certifications and past Team Lead experience, I am well-positioned to take on the role of Scrum Master, Agile Coach, Product Owner, or Agile Trainer.

EXPERTISE

ALM Tools: Jira, HP ALM, TFS, Version One

Cloud: AWS Services (Auto Scaling, EC2, IAM, RDS, S3)

Collaboration Tools: Confluence, SharePoint

Methodologies: Agile, BDD, Kanban, LeSS, SAFe 5.0®, Scrum, Lean Six Sigma, TDD, Waterfall IDEs: Brackets, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Visual Age, VB Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm

Languages & Interfaces: AJAX, ASP.NET, CSS, C#, DB2, DOM, HTML, Java, JavaScript, JSON, MongoDB,

MySQL, MS SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL, VB.NET, XML, XPath

Libraries & Run-times: Bootstrap, Bulma, Node.js, jQuery

QA Testing Tools & Frameworks: Cucumber, Docker, Gherkin, HP Quality Center 12x, Postman, SoapUI, US Bank

ETM Automation Framework, XML Spy, Selenium Webdriver, Cypress

Versioning: Babel, Git, GitHub, Webpack

Wireframes: Figma, Sketch

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Tester / Software Automation Tester, - US Bank, MN - March 2014 - Dec 2018

- Automated test scripts for multiple applications using Java and Selenium and US Bank framework
- Trained department in Agile practices
- Performed API testing using Postman
- Created DB to track project estimates.
- Led multi-department testing efforts as a PFAM Test Lead
- Created project documentation including comprehensive test strategies, test plans, and test cases
- Trained coworkers to use US Banks ETM Automation Framework

Software Development Team Lead, - US Bank, MN - March 2010 - March 2014

- Created project plans and maintained budgets for a nine-person team
- Recruited, hired, trained and supervised a staff of developers and contractors
- Managed vendor relations and resolved financial and technical issues
- Lead numerous multi-department upgrade and DR efforts of the FileNet core infrastructure
- Consulted with business customers and development team throughout the project lifecycle to determine requirements, identify business issues and needs, and assess business system solutions
- Translated business needs into detailed systems requirements; created business process flows, elaborate test plans, and user guides
- Lead Security Community of Practice meetings.

Software Developer - US Bank, MN - April 2001 - March 2010

- Wrote extensive software to feed FileNet Workflow software using .NET and Java resulting in \$1 Million dollars in savings per year
- Created numerous enterprise software services for the retrieval of FileNet based Document Images
- Configured Workflow Systems using IBM's FileNet P8 and BPF
- Developed banks first self-healing server strategy for automated application recovery
- Consolidated banks enterprise fax servers into a Rightfax server farm with automated active DR failover
- Developed data extraction systems for loan sales using Java
- Created active DR environment for FileNet based Document Imaging systems
- Created numerous document retrieval API's using Java

LAN Administrator - US Bank, MN - March 1998 - April 2001

- Designed banks first web-based Electronic Document Delivery system. Saved bank over \$1 Million a year in mailing costs
- Created a departmental website to document processes resulting in a two-year audit pass
- Managed and installed servers, workstation and organized departmental moves
- Hired and managed contractors and full-time employee in addition to managing the budget

EDUCATION

Master of Software Engineering and Management

University of St. Thomas, St Paul, MN

Completed 21 of 42 credits

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Accounting Minnesota State University, Mankato, MN

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Excellent communication skills with a focus on team building and customer relations
- Able to learn new technologies quickly, and exceptional problem-solving abilities
- Excel at identifying risks and implement effective mitigation strategies
- Strong, forward-thinking innovation skills

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- Started US Bank Test Automation (Community of Practice)
- Toastmasters (US Bank)

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS - AWS Certified Developer (working toward)

• LeSS - Certified LeSS Practitioner (2020)

• RTE - Certified SAFe 5® Release Train Engineer (2020)

POPM - Certified SAFe 5® Product Owner/Product Manager (2020)

SASM - Certified SAFe 5® Advanced Scrum Master (2020)
 SDP - Certified SAFe 5® DevOps Practitioner (2020)

SMM - Certified SAFe 5[®] Scrum Master (2020)

SPC - Certified SAFe 5® Program Consultant (2020)

Lean Six Sigma - Certified Green Belt (2019)

ICP-ACC - Certified Professional in Agile Coaching (2018)

CSM - Certified Scrum Master (2018)

PMP - Project Management Professional (Expired 2018)

AWARDS

• Found at - linkedin.com/in/john-leintz

Bronze Shield Award (02/2018) - Awarded for creation of Agile training session

Bronze Shield Award (02/2018) - Awarded for providing a high level of service for US Banks Loan Imaging system

Bronze Shield Award (12/2017) - Awarded for the development of a database for estimate tracking

Bronze Shield Award (10/2016) - Awarded for providing a high level of service for US Banks Loan Imaging system